PABLO MANDIOLA

251 W 97th Street, Apt. 5F, New York, NY 10025 (347) 720 4131 | pablo.mandiola@nyu.edu

Technology professional with 3+ years of experience implementing digital products in the public and private sector, passionate about the power of data, innovation and technology to transform urban life and improve how governments work for their citizens. Holding a graduate degree in public policy and currently pursuing a second degree in urban informatics, brings critical thinking and product development together with strong technical skills in data science and analytics.

EDUCATION

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY, Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics

New York, NY

August 2019

Civic Analytics Fellow (2019), Urban Intelligence Lab at NYU Marron Institute of Urban Management Coursework: Principles of Urban Informatics, Applied Data Science, Big Data Analysis, Machine Learning

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, School of International and Public Affairs Master of Public Administration, Urban Policy

New York, NY

May 2018

Research Assistant (2017), Tech & Policy Initiative; Teacher Assistant (2017-2018), Microeconomic Analysis for Public Affairs Coursework: Urban Economics, Policies for Urban Sustainability, Big Data for Public Policy, Tech & Future of Governance

PONTIFICIA UNIVERSIDAD CATOLICA, School of Engineering

Santiago, Chile

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering | Professional Degree in Information Technology

December 2011

Graduated with Maximum Distinction and ranked top 5%

Teaching Assistant (2007-2011): Intro to Programming, Data and Process Modeling, Computer Architecture, Technologies for BI

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MENTORPRO, EdTech Startup

New York, NY

Technology Lead

July 2018 - present

- Devise and implement the first version of the product, a video platform for schools to promote instructional feedback
- Startup member of StartEd incubator, winner of the Milken-Penn GSE Competition 2018, and CORFO Seed Fund 2018

RIPLEY, Major Retail Company in Chile and Peru

Santiago, Chile June 2014 - December 2015

- Project Manager | Department of Ecommerce Innovation and Development
- Re-engineered the checkout funnel, increasing the conversion rate more than 20% in mobile and desktop websites
- Pioneered the design and development of the first mobile app for the online store for iPhone and Android
- Led projects to enable a one-click payment solution and electronic billing for online B2B sales
- · Automated daily reports with detailed information on published products, available stock, and sales

MINISTRY OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT

Santiago, Chile

Project Manager | Information Technology Division

May 2013 - May 2014

- Collaborated in the design of a new rent subsidy as technical counterpart to simplify and modernize the policy's operation process
- Planned the information system for the rent subsidy program, project winner of the Public Innovation Challenge 2014
- Reduced US\$400K/year in operating costs by automating and systemizing manual processes of the new subsidy program

MINISTRY OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT

Santiago, Chile

Policy Analyst | Housing Policy Division

April 2012 - April 2013

- Created a real-time reporting system with information on subsidy applications, delivery of housing solutions and budget tracking
- Implemented an automated data repository with historical information to facilitate data-driven analyses and program evaluations
- Headed the creation of "Tu Vivienda" project, a website for subsidized housing listings
- Designed and managed the development of a subsidy simulator, an interactive website to assist people in finding housing programs

CLOCKWISE, Technology Solutions for Staff and Warehouse Management Developer

Santiago, Chile

December 2010 - March 2012

- Developed a mobile application for iPhone and iPad for staff tracking using face recognition
- Co-founded BiometryCloud, a cloud-based face recognition service; project winner of Startup Chile 2011

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Scholarships / Awards: Columbia SIPA Fellowship; Becas Chile Scholarship; NYU CUSP Fellowship

Data / Research tools: SQL, Python, Pandas: Proficient; Spark, R, Stata, ArcGIS: Intermediate

Volunteer: Three months community work in rural Mozambique (2016); Founding member of Arde nonprofit in Chile (2007-2011)